What's wrong?
Did you bite your tongue?
My tooth feels kind of wobbly.
Don't touch it! Don't touch it!
What should I do?
Hm... An adult tooth will be coming in underneath it, so just leave it alone.
Would you like me to make porridge from your rice for you?
No, I'll be fine if I eat it slowly.
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
Sign: Culture Festival
Ah, Daikichi!
Hey.
W-What is it?
That drawing's mine!
Kaga Rin
Your dad is always the one who comes to these things, huh?
Yeah...
Although he's not my dad.
Huh?! He's not?!
Well, isn't that great.
Hey, hey! Rin-chan's the best at drawing in Class B.
Really?
I bet you could be a mangaka.
No way!
You could!
Papa!
Over here!
Sorry I'm late.
This stylish guy is... a father?
So cool!
Lucky!
He's really tall!
By the way, Sayaka-chan said her dad is 31, just like you!
You've got to be kidding me!
Really? What a pleasant coincidence.
Papa's a model!
Wow!
Hey, Sayaka!
I've only done a little bit.
It was when I was younger...
I think I might have seen you in our company's catalogue...
Really?!
Excuse me...
But if it's not too much trouble, can I ask the name of your company?
Yes, that's probably me!
I'm so grateful!
He's cheerful, isn't he?
This is so embarrassing...
Nowadays, I'm an office manager, too.
Really?
That kind of feels like a waste...
Modeling's the sort of job where you don't really know where your next paycheck is coming from,
so when my daughter was born, I decided to call it quits.
I see...
Back then, I did nothing but drink and complain about work...
Hey, Micchan!
Nabe-chin! It's been a while!
We're old classmates.
We both come from around this area.
He has a kid, too; a boy in Class A.
This is Rin-chan's father, Daikichi-san.
He's the same age as us.
Really? Nice to meet you!
Likewise.
These two seem like the kind who really look out for their kids.
Daikichi!
I'm a butcher.
My shop's on the corner of the nearby shopping district.
Ah, we often buy croquettes there and eat them on the way home.
Really? Glad to hear it!
Me, too! Me, too!
I know, I know!
Looks like I've befriended a couple of other fathers.
In a way, my world might be wider now than it was before.
Hello.
Hello!
It's grown very cold all of a sudden, hasn't it?
Yes.
It looks like the kids have already gone to the gym.
I hope he's remembered to wear his jacket.
Yeah...
Nitani
Kouki
Wow, he's really good!
Really?
Well, it must have been so much work to...
Hey, kid... Everyone's gone to the gym already.
Seriously?!
Crap. The teacher's going to yell at me!
Boys can be so awful sometimes...
So cute! How many months old is she?
Almost ten months.
Babies are so lovely.
This is so nostalgic...
And then last week, our kid got the flu...
Sorry to bother you...
Really? That must have been hard on you.
Not at all.
Is it that season already?
Even if their fever falls, you have to keep them out of school for two days, right?
To make sure it doesn't spread.
Hm... We sent him straight back to school as soon as his fever fell.
Guess you have to, right?
Can't afford to lose your job.
And he was more or less better, so I figured the virus was dying off.
Guess so.
And even if he did pass it on, nobody would know who it came from.
Shall we go?
Um... I could actually see some sense in what they were saying,
and that just depressed me more.
What they said about work...
They could have been talking about me.
Yeah, I know.
When it gets cold, I start worrying about every little thing.
But Kouki just...
Put your pyjamas on, already!
When winter passes and it starts to get warmer,
I can finally relax.
Daikichi!
Daikichi, I'm just going to get my school bag. Wait here!
Are you two stupid or something?!
Kouki, your nose!
I said that it was cold in the gym, and you should wear your jacket!
And don't run in the corridors!
Okay!
I told you not to run!
Kouki's already starting to lose his baby teeth, right?
I keep telling him that throwing them on the roof
doesn't do any good when you're in an apartment block.
TL Note: In some areas of Japan, kids throw their baby teeth onto the roof as a charm to make strong teeth grow in their place.
Lately, he won't listen to anything I say to him...
Well, I'm not one to talk...
I'd strip down to my underwear...
...and bound down the stairs two at a time.
I'd gobble up my lunch and drink my milk in one gulp.
It feels really weird telling kids not to do all of the stuff that I did.
You did all of those things, Daikichi-san?
I think it's pretty normal for a boy,
which includes Kouki, I suppose...
S-Sorry...
But if you were like that, too, then that's a load off my mind.
What's wrong? Walk with Kouki.
I don't want to!
Then how about we split into a boys' team and a girls' team?
Rin's face is a little flushed, isn't it?
Huh?
I think she has a fever.
It might get worse...
Her cheeks are much more red than usual!
It's not the flu.
For now, make sure that all of her family members wear masks.
Right!
Good news, right?
Yeah!
Huh?
Are you done?
Yeah... I feel kind of weird around here...
The doctor said that it was a stomach bug, so don't force yourself...
Yeah... I feel kind of...
Rin!
A washbowl!
Huh? Rin is...?!
Call an ambulance right away!
No, I've already taken her to the doctor, and we have medicine.
But she just won't take it!
Her fever's getting higher and higher, and she's in pain.
I suppose you didn't wrap her up warm enough?!
Now's not the time for that!
Have you tried mixing the medicine in with juice?
You always drank it right away if it was mixed with something sweet.
I'll try it.
Thanks, Mum.
Here, have a little.
It's sweet.
Just one gulp.
Daikichi.
I'm sorry to wake you so early.
How is Rin-chan?
I'm sorry!
May I come in?
Daikichi, what's with the hair?
Sure...
It's not the flu, but...
Kouki, go watch some TV over there.
Yay!
Quietly, okay?
She just fell asleep a little while ago, but...
Her fever keeps going up.
She doesn't look like she's sleeping much.
And she's not even sweating.
Has she been able to drink anything?
I was told to give her sports drinks at the very least, but...
She won't drink, and she won't eat...
I don't know what to do.
W-What is it?
You need to keep your cool!
As an adult, you have to stay calm and tell her that things are okay.
It's hard.
I've never seen her like that before.
Don't be like that. You can do it!
When children are really in trouble,
they need an adult by their side to help them.
Rin-chan will be fine as long as you're with her, Daikichi-san.
Rin-chan...
Kouki-kun's mum...
You must be thirsty.
Do you want some ice to eat?
How is it?
It feels good.
Rin, you're awake?!
Sorry, I was in the bathroom.
Daikichi-san.
Sorry...
In a little while, try having a little more ice.
If you eat too much at once, you'll shock your stomach.
Yeah.
I'll put something sweet and tasty in the freezer for you, okay?
Okay...
Sorry, you're going to be late for work, aren't you?
Rin-chan's doing really well.
She'll be fine as long as you're there for her, Daikichi-san.
Right. Thank you...
Thanks to you, too, Kouki.
Right...
Sorry, I might have to take tomorrow off, too.
If anything happens, give me a call.
Right!
Sorry for the trouble.
What are you saying?
Leave everything to us.
Thank you...
Can you eat a little?
Yeah...
When you're ill, you get to eat nothing but sweet things, huh?
See you later...
After a little more rest, you'll be all better.
Why did it have to be Rin?
I'd shrug off a bug like this in no time at all.
Damn it!
Damn it! Damn it!
Yeah?
Daikichi! Hey!
Kouki!
How are you, Rin-chan?
Does it hurt anywhere?
I'm fine.
I'll make you some yummy rice porridge now, okay?
Her fever's gone up again since this afternoon.
It's okay.
Even without a fever, your body temperature rises as the day goes on.
But just a while ago, it was more than 39 degrees.
Here you go! Put this in the pot.
Right.
Daikichi...
Water...
It looks really good...
I made some for you too, Daikichi-san.
Daikichi! Rin needs water!
Right!
Kouki, you stay in here. You don't want to catch it.
I don't care if I get it.
You should care!
Thanks...
Thank you, Kouki-kun...
Kouki, since you're around, Rin's really relaxed.
Yeah...
Here you go, Rin-chan. Have a little.
Don't worry. Kouki eats this when he gets sick, as well.
It's special porridge that'll make you well in no time at all!
Kouki-kun has it, too?
Whenever he eats it, he gets better just like that.
It's good!
Daikichi!
Rin. Are you okay?
Yeah. I feel good!
I'm hungry!
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Can you tell your mum thanks for everything?
She looked after Rin, so...
Hey, can I go home with you guys?
Again?!
Your mum's supposed to come here to pick you up!
But mum's in bed with a cold.
Huh?! Are you serious?!